# Eric D. Torres

New Orleans, LA 70116

Cell Phone: 504-722-0278 \* E-mail: etorresnotary@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ericdtorres/

Portfolio: https://etorres-revature.github.io/Responsive Portfolio/portfolio.html

GitHub: https://github.com/etorres-revature/

# Summary

17+ years of successful business experience. Post-graduate law & executive business degrees, combined with an analytical mindset and uncompromising work ethic with complex problem solving, relationship development, and people management. Made a career shift to become a technical professional through a paid program with Revature for training and industry immersion to gain technical experience, object-oriented programming education and certifications for PEGA development. Ready to deploy technical skills in HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript as a full-stack web developer.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### PORTFOLIO EDGE |

https://github.com/etorres-revature/Lucky Mountaineers | https://etorres-revature.github.io/Lucky Mountaineers/

Web app designed to provide up-to-the minute information about stocks. Information provided includes: Company Description, chart of previous twelve months prices, current quote information, and long-term price information.

**Responsible for** the front-end design, back-end development, and data integration.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, server-side APIs, Chart.js.

## Weather Dashboard |

https://github.com/etorres-revature/Weather Dashboard | https://etorres-revature.github.io/Weather Dashboard/

Web app that provides current and five-day weather information for any location around the world. Popular cities are provided, as well as local storage of previously searched cities.

Responsible for front-end, back-end, data integration, local storage.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap 4, JavaScript, AJAX, server-side APIs, Moment.is.

<u>JS Code Quiz</u> | <a href="https://github.com/etorres-revature/JavaScript">https://github.com/etorres-revature/JavaScript</a> Code Quiz Challenge | <a href="https://etorres-revature.github.io/JavaScript">https://etorres-revature.github.io/JavaScript</a> Code Quiz Challenge/

Ten question quiz that displays the capabilities of JavaScript while testing the user's knowledge. Dynamic display of end-game picture/messages; local storage of user initials/score; button to change background color; constant shuffle of title colors from array; display of current score; display of game clock; and display of current question.

Responsible for front-end design, local storage, additional functionality.

<u>Technologies</u>: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap 4, JavaScript

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Low-Code/No-Code: PEGA Platform

Languages: HTML5; CSS, JavaScript

Databases: SQL; MongoDB

Frameworks/libraries: Chart.js; Moment.js

**Development Tools**: GitHub; Git Bash; client-side APIs; server-side APIs

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Software Developer | 2020

Revature

- Intensive, three-month training bootcamp with exposure to principles of object-oriented programming, Java, SQL, CSS, HTML, AWS, and PEGA platform.
- Developed three projects 1 full-stack Java and 2 PEGA platform.

#### Associate Attorney | 2017-2019

ROBERT J. ELLIS LAW FIRM, LLC; New Orleans, LA

- Worked as associate for a solo practice focusing on municipal and state government solutions in general litigation, planning and zoning, and regulatory compliance matters.
- Conduct research and writing for legal memoranda and appellate briefs. Prepare, review, and file motions and petitions. Meet with agency staff, opposing counsel, clients, and other parties and stakeholders.
- Client portfolio includes developers, commercial and residential property owners, medical institutions, universities, area businesses, and state and local agencies.

# **Interim Executive Director | 2017**

LOUISIANA STATE BOARD OF MEDICAL EXAMINERS; New Orleans, LA

- Served as Interim Executive Director during search process for an M.D. to permanently fill the role. Directed a staff of 40 with accountability for licensing 31,000 physicians and 13 other classifications of allied health professionals.
- Implemented a \$7.8 million budget, represented the Board at the Louisiana Legislature, worked with stakeholders on issues
  of policy, including medical marijuana, meaningful oversight, opioid abuse, and Health Professional Shortage Areas (HPSAs).

# <u>Business Operations Director / Health Promotion Unit | 2014-2016</u>

LOUISIANA DEPT. OF HEALTH & HOSPITALS; Baton Rouge, LA

- Competitively selected as BOD of the Health Promotion Unit in the Office of Public Health in executing deliverables through facilitation of CDC grants. Managed Health Promotion Budget of ~\$5 million dollars in Cooperative Agreements.
- Drafted, routed, edited, and monitored contracts for payment and performance. Coordinated HR, Planning & Evaluation Sessions, Onboarding, and Policies & Procedures. Initiated Governor's state-wide Well-Ahead Louisiana campaign.

### Program Support Coordinator / Assistant to the Undersecretary | 2012-2014

LOUISIANA DEPT. OF HEALTH & HOSPITALS; Baton Rouge, LA

- As Program Support Coordinator (2013-2014), worked within the Program Support & Waiver Unit of the Louisiana Medical Assistance Program (Medicaid), handling two multi-million dollar rebalancing programs.
- Coordinated with the Centers for Medicare & Medicaid Services and across agencies at DHH. Managed administrative, non-programmatic aspects of Operational Protocol, Annual Budget, and Quarterly Services Reporting.
- As Assistant to the Undersecretary (2012-2013), assisted in developing and implementing \$1.2 billion public-private partnerships for LSU Health Sciences Center safety net hospitals.
- Coordinating with 9 Louisiana hospitals on utilization and supplemental Medicaid payments. Worked with DHH staff, partner hospital executives, outside counsel, LSUHSC administrative staff, and others to execute all aspects of CEAs.
- In Spring 2013, assigned to Program Integrity-Compliance Unit, overseeing investigations and codified sanctions. Processed Mandatory & Permissive Exclusions and made recommendations on disclosure of ownership for Provider Enrollment.
- In Q1 & Q2 2012, closed 20+ files resulting in \$1 million+ dollar return to the LA Medicaid Program. Assigned to a high-volume docket of administrative adjudications and investigations.
- Prepared motions and pleadings to file with the Division of Administrative Law. Crafted discovery, presented cases before the Administrative Law Judge, and represented the department at the 19<sup>th</sup> Judicial District Court & Federal District Courts.

#### **EDUCATION**

### Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development | 2021 (anticipated)

# Juris Doctor (JD) | Admitted to Practice, Louisiana Bar | 2010

LOYOLA UNIVERSITY COLLEGE OF LAW; New Orleans, LA

Major: Civil Law | Evening Division

**Leadership:** Honor Board Evening Division Representative

# Bachelor of Arts (BA) | 2001

TULANE UNIVERSITY; New Orleans, LA

Major: Political Science